Finding Aid for Robert J. Shepard papers, 1968-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert J. Shepard papers
1968-1969
Robert J. Shepard
18 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes
2 volumes
1 folder
11.8 GB
0445 Aa 2
Soldier with C-Company, 307th Engineering Platoon, 3rd Brigade, 82nd Airborne Division, in Vietnam, includes recorded letters sent home while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969; and photographic snapshots of Shepard, other members of his company, and the areas in Vietnam where they were stationed.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Robert Shepard collection was donated by Jolene Michaels (donor no. 9425, in two accessions in 2004.
No further additions to the collecltion are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Robert J. Shepard was a soldier with C-Company, 307th Engineering Platoon, 3rd Brigade, 82nd Airborne Division, in Vietnam, 1968-1969. His family lived in Grand Rapids, Michigan.
The Robert Shepard collection includes recorded letters (18, 3-inch rel-to-reel tapes) sent home while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969; and photographic snapshots of Shepard, other members of his company, and the areas in Vietnam where they were stationed. The Photogaphs consist of two photo albums and two envelopes full of loose photographs as well as a CD of scans of the photo albums creted by the donor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Shepard, Robert J.; Military life--American--Vietnam.; Military art and science.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Military life.; CD-ROMs.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Shepard, Robert J.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Personal narratives, American.; Soldiers--United States.; CD-ROMs.
Contributors:
corpname; persname; geogname
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.; Photographs.
- Photographs, 1968-1969
  - Photograph album (Pictures of Robert and All the Guys) (Box 1)
  - Photograph album (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1 folders (Box 1)
  - Digitized Photgraphs (scans of the phto albums), 1 optical disks CDs (Box 1)
- Sound Recordings
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] December 1968, 1968 December; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-1-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Two individuals talking.Caption: 7 Months, First few days of Dec. '68)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-1-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 7 Months, First few days of Dec. '68)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Between Christmas and New Year's 1968, 1968 December; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-2-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: Between hristmas and New Year's '68)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-2-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969.Caption: Between hristmas and New Year's '68)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] December 25, 1968, 1968 December 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-3-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 25 Dec. '68, Front Black Side 2 Full)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] January 19, 1969, 1969 January 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-4-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Shepard discusses extending his tour in Vietnam.Caption: Not Yet Extended)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Extended for six more months, 1969 January 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-5-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 48 Days to Leave; Extended for Six More months, in Viet-Nam, Bud buy me a car.)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Ext After Ext, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-6-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: Ext after ext)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-6-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. This recording is a short letter and includes recordings of military radio stations. Caption: Ext after ext)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Extension did not go through 31st FC3, 1969 February 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-7-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Shepard discusses his rejected extension.Caption: 31 Feb?)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-7-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 31 Feb?)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] February 27, 1969, 1969 February 27; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-8-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Discussing attacks and battles.Caption: 101 Days to go.)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-8-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Recording of radio broadcast, no other content.)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] March 1, 1969, 1969 March 01; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-9-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Discussing the possibility of coming home in March.Caption: Maybe coming home in March 15th, 56? 51 Days to go)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Early March 1969, 1969 March; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-10-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. )
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-10-2]; mp3 file; (No vocal content, recording of popular music from Army radio.)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] March 11, 1969, 1969 March 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch, 3 ¾ ips
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-11-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Tape box notes that bombs can be heard in the background.Caption: Hear bombs in background 85 Days to Go)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-11-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Tape box notes that bombs can be heard in the background. References a B-52 bombing strike occurring at the time.Caption: Hear bombs in background 85 Days to Go)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] March 13, 1969, 1969 March 13; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-12-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. )
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-12-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. References gunfire in the background and poker games.)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] March 30, 1969, 1969 March 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-13-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Shepard references gunfire and attacks nearby during recording.Caption: 71 days to go.)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-13-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Shepard talks about his feelings about the war.Caption: 71 Days to go )
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] April 3, 1969, 1969 April 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-14-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. )
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] April 6, 1969, 1969 April 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-15-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 10 months to go Today)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-15-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. )
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Late April 1969, 1969 April 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-16-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. This recording appears to have been recorded at different times.)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] May 1st or 3rd 1969, 1969 May; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-17-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Caption: 37 Days to go)
  - [Letter from Robert Shepard:] Bob and friends, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 3 inch
    - [Part 1], [0445-SR-18-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. Recordings of several other associates of Shepard.)
    - [Part 2], [0445-SR-18-2]; mp3 file; (Recorded letters sent home by Shepard while stationed in Vietnam, 1968-1969. )